C. Stowe Myers Papers
C. Stowe Myers Papers
1930-1995
Myers, C. Stowe (Charles Stowe).
6 linear ft.
American industrial designer. Correspondence-subject files, memorabilia, photographs, audio and video recordings, and slides.
2741080
Biographical History
Charles Stowe Myers (1906-1995) was an American industrial designer. Born in Altoona, Pennsylvania, he graduated from the University of Pennsylvania in 1930 and went to work for Norman bel Geddes in 1932. In 1934 he joined Walter Dorwin Teague; while with Teague he worked on exhibits for the New York World's Fair (1939-1940) as well as several military designs. In 1950 he joined Raymond Loewy and by 1952 was managing Loewy's Chicago office. In 1954 he left to open his own firm, Stowe Myers Design, in Evanston, Illinois. Between 1954 and 1970 the firm's projects ranged from Tinkertoy packaging to exhibits at the 1959 International Trade Fair in Casablanca. Myers was a founding member of the the West Coast Chapter of the Society of Industrial Designers and active in SID's New York and Chicago chapters as well. After retiring in 1976 he turned to painting, and was named official artist of the US Air Force in 1978.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The C. Stowe Myers Papers consists of correspondence-subject files, memorabilia, photographs, recordings, and slides.
Correspondence-subject files include correspondence with other designers such as Rayond Loewy and Walter Dorwin Teague, material from organizations such as the American Society of Industrial Designers, and topical folders including trade fairs in Tripoli and Washington, D.C. and military ordnance manuals for projects in which Myers was involved.
Memorabilia contains assorted material relating to Myers' career, including awards and certificates, career information, stationery (business letterhead, envelopes, business cards, etc.), and a design portfolio. The portfolio was originally housed in a battered and non-descript black case; it has been removed from the case and placed into archival boxes.
The bulk of the Photographs are professional in nature, including Walter Dorwin Teague's offices in New York and Los Angeles, and various design projects. There are a few candid photos of Myers, and two folders of photographs of his watercolor artwork.
Recordings contains interviews with Myers and a piece (possibly a speech) on early industrial design.
A considerable number of Slides completes the collection. Most are unlabeled, and remain in original containers and original order.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged alphabetically by type or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Industrial Design; Loewy, Raymond, 1893-1986.; Myers, C. Stowe (Charles Stowe); Teague, Walter Dorwin, 1883-1960.; Industrial Designers Society of America.; New York World's Fair (1939-1940: New York, N.Y.); Industrial design -- United States.; Industrial designers -- United States.; Packaging -- Design.; Brochures.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Posters.; Renderings (drawings); Slides (photographs); Industrial designers.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Charles Myers, 1997.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Aarnio, Reino, 1957; 1960 (Box 1)
  - American Society of Industrial Designers (ASID) (Box 1)
  - Articles and press releases, 1947-1963; a few about Myers, most about other designers, products, etc.; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Bethlehem Steel descriptive specifications, 1941 (Box 1)
  - Dreyfus, Henry, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Gun Director Mark 37 and Mods 31 manual, Mar 1945; includes copy of congratulatory letter to Myers from Bureau of Naval Ordnance (Box 1)
  - IDSA, includes bylaws, newsletters, etc. (Box 1)
  - Koeber, Theodore, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Loewy, Raymond, 1952-1954 (Box 1)
  - Lueloff, Jorie (NBC), 1980 (Box 1)
  - Mackie, David, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Mox, Dana, 1960 (Box 1)
  - Product announcements, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Rheem design book, to 1957; 3-ring notebook of plumbing designs (Oversize 1)
  - River Rouge/Teague article (Box 2)
  - Rutter, Sheldon, 1958; 1960 (Box 2)
  - Speech, "Industrial designers and their clients" by Myers, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Swedish Embassy, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Technical Information Manual for the type T5 ski mount for the 75mm howitzer carriage M3A3 (Box 2)
  - Teague, Walter Dorwin, 1948; 1953-1957,; 1961-1962,; 1981; includes announcement of Myers' partnership (Box 2)
  - Tripoli Trade Fair, 1962 (Box 2)
    See also Photographs: Trade Fair photobook, Tripoli.
  - Twyeffort, Elizabeth, 1980 (Box 2)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1930; 1979; includes Myers' grades (Box 2)
  - War - personal, 1942-1943 (Box 2)
  - Washington, DC, 1959; most appears to pertain to a trade show; correspondents include "Mike" and "Tubby" (Box 2)
  - Western Museum Conference, 1947 (Box 2)
  - White, Roger G., 1960 (Box 2)
- Memorabilia
  - Awards and certificates, 1945; 1957 (Box 2)
  - Career synopsis, cv's, obituaries (Box 2)
  - Design portfolio, originally in attache case; removed (Oversize 2)
  - Design portfolio (cont.) (Oversize 3)
  - Living Legends of Chicago Design (Box 2)
  - Stationery, includes business cards, letterhead (Box 2)
  - Stationery, includes business cards, letterhead (Box 2)
  - Stowe Myers ID promo, branding ideas for firm; includes correspondence with Mike Joss, IDSA (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 3)
- Photographs
  - Air Force artwork, Stowe's paintings (Box 3)
  - Design snapshots, miscellaneous, plastio comb-bound book (Box 3)
  - Linear Syntec design (Box 3)
  - Loewy (Box 3)
  - Navy gunport seal and gun director work with Teague office (Box 3)
  - Portraits of Stowe Myers taken in 1990 by his son, Charles S. Myers III (Box 3)
  - Renderings, photographs of (Box 3)
  - River Rouge photo book, 1937-1938 (Oversize 1)
  - Teague office, Los Angeles, includes innovative gas station (Box 3)
  - Teague office, New York City (Box 3)
  - Teague office, New York World's Fair, 1939-1940 (Box 3)
  - Trade Fair photo book, Casablanca and Tunis, 1959 (Oversize 4)
  - Trade Fair photo book, Tripoli, 1962 (Oversize 4)
  - Watercolors, Stowe's personal artwork (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, unidentified photos (Box 3)
- Recordings
  - Bio and industrial design career for an article in The Air Force Artists newsletter, 2/8/89; audiorecording (Box 4)
  - Early Industrial Design for NEA Archives, 5/3/90; audiorecording (Box 4)
  - Tape #1 Interview by Vicki Matranga, Feb 10-11, 1995; VHS tape (Box 4)
  - Tape #2 (continued), VHS tape (Box 4)
  - Tape #3 Teague office, early 1940s; VHS tape (Box 4)
- Slides
  - Argus box of 4 slide trays (Box 5)
  - Argus 80 slide tray (Box 5)
  - Argus 80 slide tray (Box 5)
  - Filmdex slide keepers, 1939; NY World's Fair; 3 boxes (Box 5)
  - Grey metal slide box (Box 5)
  - #1 Air Force, Parker Pen, CMI Gibson, Watertower Place signage, Tinkertoy, Ency. Brit., 3-ring binder (Oversize 5)
  - #2, Air Force, Ency. Brit., 3-ring binder (Oversize 6)
  - Rheems Topics, blue plastic box (Box 5)
  - White metal lid slide box (Box 5)